Yamada? Are you okay?
山田？怎么了？
Your hair hit my eye.
头发刺到我的眼睛…
Really? Oh, I'm sorry.
不会吧？抱歉
Are you okay? Is it stuck in your eye?
没事吧？跑进眼睛了？
Show me!
让我看看
Which eye was it?
是哪只眼睛？
I'm… fine.
我已经…没事了
I'm so sorry, Yamada!
山田，抱歉哦！
You apologize too, Runa!
瑠奈，你也来道歉
I'm so… sorry!
对…对不起
I'll tie my hair up, okay?
我把头发束起来哦
Um…
那个…
I need some things from home.
我先暂时回家一趟
Oh, but…
可是…
I'll be right back.
我马上回来
All the way home and back? I don't want to take up--
来回一趟很辛苦吧 这样太不好意思…
It's fine.
没事
I live nearby.
反正很近
UGLY MORON
（笨蛋，丑女）
I don't mind
就算被霸凌
being bullied.
我也不在乎
As long as you're here, Akito.
只要有秋斗在就好
Will you stay with me forever,
就算长大了
even when we're adults?
我们也要永远在一起哦
How could I know that?
那种事我无法保证啊
Welcome!
欢迎光临
Would you like a bag?
要塑料袋吗？
Yes.
好
You buy this often, don't you?
你每次都买这个吧
It's good right? This brand makes good tea.
这个牌子的茶都很好喝嘛
Oh, yeah.
呃…是的
I like it too.
我也很喜欢这个茶
Thank you, come again!
谢谢光临
Excuse me…!
请问…
If you don't mind,
如果方便的话
could I ask your name?
可以请教你的名字吗？
That uniform you wear
看你平常穿的制服…
is for Tosei Academy, right?
你是念东成学院吧
I'm a graduate!
我是那里的毕业生
I've been wanting
从之前开始…
to talk to you at some point.
我就很想跟你聊聊天
Sorry, I'm in a hurry.
抱歉，我有急事
Of course you are.
我想也是
FORGIVE ME…
（不好意思…）
Why is she making that face?
为什么…要露出那种脸？
I really am in a hurry
我有急事
and what would I talk about with a convenience store employee?
也不知道要跟超商店员聊什么
You've always been like that.
你就是这样的人嘛
I don't get it.
完全搞不懂
They make no sense.
我讨厌这样
I should stay away from them.
想必还是别靠近比较好
I'm back.
我回来了
They're gone?
没人在？
YAMADA
（山田）
AFTER-MEAL NAP TIME
（饭后的午睡时间）
They seem to be sleeping happily.
睡得真香甜
I'd better work quietly.
静静地处理吧
ALL-PURPOSE
（螺丝起子组）
That was close.
好险
Sorry! I'll tie my hair up, okay?
抱歉，我把头发束起来哦
YAMADA
（山田）
Yamada!
山…田？
Huh? Why are you here?
你为什么在这里？
Why… wait!
为什么？真的假的？
I'm a fan!
我是你的粉丝！
I remember this guy.
之前好像看过这个人
What are you doing here?
你为什么会在这？
Well… a lot happened.
就是…说来话长
"A lot" what?!
说来话长是什么意思？
Give me the details!
请说明那些很长的部分
I'd… rather not.
真麻烦
Don't tell me you and Akane really are--
难不成你真的和茜…
Let me introduce you
我来介绍一下
to my new boyfriend.
这是我的新男友
Not true.
并不是
No, that can't be.
不，不可能
No matter how you look at it,
现在仔细想想
Akane clearly put you up to it.
当时一定是茜在演闹剧
She always puts on a big show.
毕竟那家伙很爱面子
Plus,
更重要的是
I follow all your social media activity.
我每秒都会确认山田所有社群账号
Steady the course! No sign of women!
毫无异常，没有女色
Everything is as it should be!
和平常一模一样
So don't worry, I haven't gotten any funny ideas.
我完全没有误会，放心吧
Oh, right.
对了
Actually,
其实我…
I came
是有东西要还给茜
to return some things.
才会过来一趟
I don't see her on campus at all
我们在大学完全不会见面
and I have no way of contacting her now.
我现在也没管道连络得到她
She made me a lot of box lunches
以前她为我做便当用的盒子
and other meals,
还有装饭菜的盘子
but I always forgot to return the dishes and things.
我老是会忘记还她
They had piled up quite a bit.
结果就堆了好多
I have five lunch boxes alone.
光是便当盒就有五个
I figured it'd be bad not to return them.
如果不还她，感觉也不好意思
Shouldn't you have done it earlier?
你也堆太多了吧
Well, I'm sure she doesn't want to see my face anymore.
我想她八成也不想看到我的脸
But looking at these as I was cleaning up,
但是整理完，看到这些后
I thought a lot of things over.
就让我想了很多
I made box lunches for us!
我做便当来了
I couldn't help but worry if she's doing okay.
开始担心她有没有好好生活
If I could see her smiling,
要是能看到她有精神
it would ease my mind.
我也会放心许多
I think… she's fine.
我猜…她还蛮有精神
Is that… what you want to see?
你想…看看那样的她吗？
Are you looking for peace of mind?
看了之后，好让自己放心吗？
I…
我…
think I'll go.
回去了
Sorry for the selfish request.
这么自作主张，真是抱歉
Please don't tell Akane I was here.
请你也别告诉茜我有来过
Just act like these lunch boxes appeared out of nowhere!
就当作便当盒莫名冒出来
I'd appreciate it!
交给你处理啦
Well…
好…
I'll be rooting for you in your next tournament!
下次的大赛，我也会为你加油
SILENCE
（直盯）
Um…
那个…
How long has she been there?
她从何时开始在的？
Oh, uh…
就是…
These lunch boxes…
便当盒…
appeared out of nowhere.
突然冒出来了
KEEPING HIS PROMISE EVEN THOUGH SHE CLEARLY KNOWS THE TRUTH
（说词破绽百出，但还是努力守约）
Come on!
不是吧？
Did you really think I'd believe that?
怎么可能会突然冒出来嘛
Seeing you say that with a straight face makes me laugh.
看你一脸正经地说，我都笑出来了
Thanks for handling that.
谢谢你帮忙应门
Excuse me… you can have this back.
那个…这还你
Huh?
奇怪？
Now that you mention it, my hair is down.
说起来，头发不知不觉就散开了
Yes.
是的
I took it.
是我拆的
While you were sleeping…
就在你睡觉的时候
Is that so?
是哦
Yes. I'm sorry.
是的，抱歉
Uh, why did you do that?
为什么要拆？
NOT THAT I MIND…
（是没关系啦…）
Well…
天晓得…
Somehow… I just wanted to.
就是自然而然…想这么做
I wonder why.
是为什么呢？
What… are you saying?
你…你在说什么啊？
It's Eita.
是瑛太
Hello.
辛苦了
Yes.
是的
Then can I tell you what parts I need?
那我现在能说需要的零件吗？
Hang on a second.
啊，等等
I'll write them down.
我笔记一下
Let's see…
我找找…
What was that about?
怎么回事啊？
Akane Kinoshita, eh?
是木之下茜小姐吧
Do you have a preferred shift time?
有期望的工作时段吗？
If I'm not in class,
只要大学没课
I'm happy to come anytime you need.
我随时都能来上班
That's what I like to hear.
真可靠耶
Your campus is nearby,
你的学校就在附近
so it should be an easy commute.
通勤也很轻松
Yes!
是的
Our store is pretty busy,
我们的店还蛮忙的
so I'd love it if you could come often. Is that okay?
希望你多来上班，没问题吧？
Yes! I'll do my best!
没问题，我会加油的
NEEDS THE MONEY
（缺钱）
You got a convenience store job?
超商打工？
I had no idea you were looking.
你有去投履历啊？
It's only short-term.
只是短期啦
The store is near campus.
就是学校附近的超商
The one on the main street with the long-haired manager.
在马路旁，店长是长发的那间
Tell me when your shift is finalized. I'll come by.
班表排好后告诉我，我去找你
Please do!
快来…
But why a part-time job?
但为什么要去打工？
They fixed your computer, right?
坏掉的笔电已经修好了吧？
Yeah, but…
是这样没错啦
Eita--
瑛太他…
One of the other guild members gave me parts for free.
游戏公会的人帮我免费换的零件
I'm sure they're worth a lot.
在外面买应该蛮花钱的
I can't just not pay.
完全不出钱也不好意思
I plan on asking him the cost
我打算今天上线后
when I log in today.
再问问对方细节
You're gonna wait to ask him in game, huh?
还特别在游戏里问啊
Yeah!
是啊
Well, they did help you out.
但毕竟对方这次帮了你
I guess you owe them thanks.
还是需要回礼嘛
Momo!
小桃
Oh, I've been called.
在叫我了
I've got a blind date to get to.
我正在联谊，先挂了
Let's talk more later.
下次再慢慢聊吧
Right!
好
Momo, you take too long in the restroom.
小桃，你在洗手间待真久
The men are waiting.
男生们都在等了
Sorry! A friend of mine called.
抱歉，刚好有朋友打电话来
-A friend? -Akane.
-朋友？ -就是茜
She got a part-time job.
她说她开始打工了
Oh, Kinoshita!
原来是木之下啊
I haven't seen her at any blind dates recently.
话说她最近都没来联谊耶
She's busy playing online video games.
她现在正忙着玩在线游戏
Just let her be.
不需要管她
Okay! Today's the day I find my prince!
好，今天一定要找到王子
THE BLIND DATE'S OVER. NO PRINCE TODAY EITHER.
（联谊结束了 今天也没找到我的王子）
TEARS
（哭）
Too bad.
哎呀
Momo can't find a man who meets her standards.
看来一直遇不到小桃的理想对象
"If you give up, it's game over."
“要是放弃，比赛就结束咯”…传送
Still…
但是…
Is it even possible to meet someone
邂逅瞬间就知道对方是真命天菜
who immediately seems perfect?
这在现实中有可能发生吗？
SYSTEM: AKANE HAS LOGGED IN
（Akane上线了）
Princess Ruri!
瑠璃姬
Akane!
Akane
Long time no see!
好久不见
Hello!
哈啰…
I can't believe that's Eita.
这个人是瑛太嘛…
NO INHIBITIONS TYPE WHO KEEPS HER SENSES
（本性，恢复理智的类型）
What's going on?
你在做什么？
I was having a guild meeting with the Submas.
我正好在和副会开公会会议
The Submas?
副会？
SUBMAS MEANS "SUB-MASTER"
（副会=公会副会长）
Over there! Just look!
就在那里
Right there!
在那里
Whoa! They're tiny!
好小！
The submas is tiny!
副会长好小！
It's a race called a "micronest."
是叫做微生物的种族哦
They're very small outside of battle.
非战斗模式时都很小
Most consider them a gimmick race,
虽然大家常开这个种族的玩笑
but if you raise them right, they can become very strong!
但是只要练得好，就会很强哦
Right, Takezo?
对吧，takezo？
Hello, Akane!
Akane，哈啰
I'm Takeza Kamota.
我叫鸭田竹藏
My character is named Takezo.
角色名称是 罗马拼音的“takezo”
Mr. Kamota?!
鸭田先生？
Tsk, tsk.
错…
Here, he's Takezo.
在这里要叫他takezo
Oh, right. Sorry.
对耶，抱歉
Takezo doesn't exit the dungeon often,
takezo平常都窝在地下城
so it's rare to see him in the guild!
很难得出现在公会房间嘛
He's quite cute,
虽然可爱
but if the camera pulls back,
但是画面只要稍微后退
I can't see him at all.
就会看不到takezo了
I know, right?
我懂
Oh, that's right. I wanted to ask you something, Princess Ruri.
对了，我有事想问瑠璃姬
Oh yeah? What?
什么？
"I was wondering how much I owe"
前阵子帮我修好电脑的费用
"for repairing my computer."
大概花了多少呢？
I'M NOT TELLING YOU!
（是秘密）
Huh? But why?
为什么不说？
NO WORRIES. THEY WERE ALL SPARE PARTS.
（零件都是二手，不用在意啦）
I can't just accept that.
这样我会过意不去啦
What do I do, Takezo?
怎么办呢，takezo？
I understand how both of you feel.
我能明白你们两人的心情
It's a tough one.
这问题真是困难啊
As a compromise,
那就折衷一下
why not ask Akane to take part in our plan?
请Akane 参加刚才说的计划如何？
That's a great idea!
这真是个好点子
Plan?
计划？
HAUNTED MAID CAFE
（鬼屋女仆咖啡厅）
HOT DOGS
（热狗）
Oh, wow! It's Yamada!
天啊，是山田学长
Huh? Where?
不会吧？
Should we try talking to him?
要向他搭话吗？
What about?
要说什么好？
Um…
这个嘛…
About video games or something?
像是游戏的话题
What's that thing he does?
那个叫什么啊？
F-P…
是FP…
Oh, someone else is coming.
好像有人来了
Hey.
辛苦啦
Hi.
辛苦了
Taking out the trash?
去丢垃圾吗？
Looks heavy.
感觉很重
As always, the girls have their eyes glued on you.
女生对你的视线还是一样火热
If you entered the Mr. Academy contest, you'd be sure to win.
你去参加校草选拔肯定是冠军
It's such a waste that you keep saying no.
今年却还是拒绝出赛，真可惜
Even so, the organizers
不过委员会的人
still haven't given up.
似乎还没放弃的样子哦
They asked me to convince you.
他们来拜托我说服你
If Yamada ever gets a girlfriend,
如果山田交到女友
I bet some girls will be in tears.
一定有人会哭吧
-There'll be a riot at school. -Your point…?
-校内可能会一团乱 -然后呢？
Oh, well.
没事
Are you free today?
今天闲吗？
Wanna game when we get home?
回去后要不要玩游戏？
SURE
（好啊）
Yamada-kun!
山田
Your phone's been ringing non-stop!
你的手机在教室响个不停哦
Huh? What was that reaction?
你刚才那是什么态度？
You can do better than that.
可以再亲切一点吧？
How about…
例如…
-Something like that. -Non-stop?
-如果是“一直在响” -像是这样子啊
-Or… -It must be Eita.
-大概是瑛太吧 -或者是…
"Thanks, kittens."
“谢谢，各位小猫们”之类的
Or…
还有…
The vibrations made your desk rattle.
手机震动撞得桌子很吵
I put a towel under it.
我就铺了毛巾
WORLD HISTORY
（《详说世界史》）
Sorry for the trouble.
对不起
Thank you very much,
谢谢你
Tsubaki.
桩同学
I watched your match yesterday.
昨天的比赛，我有看转播
Your aim was off.
瞄准得太粗糙
Reactions were dull.
反应太慢
Losing your touch?
你实力变差了？
You spend too much time on that MMO.
你该不会只顾着玩什么MMO
Maybe you stink at FPS now?
让FPS的实力变差了？
Yesterday's server was overseas.
昨天比赛连的是外国服务器
The lag was--
延迟很严重…
Don't blame the network.
不要把网络环境当借口
Right.
好的
GUILD NEWS:
（公会速报）
CHOCOLATE RABBIT
（今年我们公会，巧克力兔）
WILL ONCE AGAIN PARTICIPATE IN THE TOSEI SCHOOL FESTIVAL
（也要参加即将举办的 东成学院校庆一般开放日）
WE NEED YOU TO ARRANGE TICKETS FOR THE FOLLOWING MEMBERS:
（请山田帮忙准备参加成员的门票 以下是参加成员）
EITA SASAKI, RUNA SASAKI, TAKEZO KAMOTA, AND… AKANE KINOSHITA (SPONSOR)
（佐佐木瑛太、佐佐木瑠奈 鸭田竹藏、木之下茜）
Sponsor?
赞助商？
FOS is the game you play, right?
你在玩的是FOS吗？
Yeah.
是的
Is it fun?
好玩吗？
So, uh… what's this thing?
这…这是什么？
An external graphics card.
是外接显卡盒
Keep it plugged in when you're gaming.
玩游戏的时候记得接着
The whole time?
一直接着？
Yes.
是的
THE WHOLE TIME…
（一直接着…）
Oh, but…
不过感觉上
It does seem faster than before.
笔电变得比之前更快了
The movements are all smooth.
玩起来感觉很流畅
Why's that?
为什么？
Did you fix that too?
这也帮我修好了？
You're amazing, Yamada!
山田好厉害哦
Most of them
这些零件
were spare parts that Eita had.
几乎是瑛太拿他多的过来
In addition to the graphics card,
电脑会变快，是我接显卡盒时
I replaced the old model CPU,
顺便换掉上一代的CPU
doubled your memory,
增加了记忆体
and changed your hard drive to an SSD, which is probably why it's faster.
然后把硬盘换成SSD的关系
I don't know what that means, but…
虽然我听不太懂
Is it basically an all-new computer?
该不会内部几乎全换了？
You could say that.
是啊，就是那样
Thanks again, Yamada.
谢谢你，山田
You really helped me out.
真的救了我
Not at all.
不会
HE REALLY IS GOD-LIKE…
（有够神…）
DAYS LATER
（过几天）
Today is a private event to welcome Akane back to the game.
今天是 “欢迎Akane归来私人活动”
To celebrate, the three of us will do a dungeon conquest tour!
现在三人要来一趟攻略地下城之旅
Let's do it!
请多指教
THIRD MEMBER
（第三人）
There's no need to be nervous.
不用那么紧张啦
At your level,
这次要去的地方
you should have no problem
以Akane的等级也能轻松攻略
with today's course, Akane.
尽管放心吧
We'll do our best to support you too.
我们也会全力协助
He's so kind in the game and in real life!
不管在游戏还是现实都好温柔
His avatar sort of suits him too.
造型也很有鸭田先生的风格
I like it!
我还蛮喜欢的
Off to the dungeon!
朝地下城前进！
-Yeah!
好！
Better pull my weight.
我要设法派上用场，加油吧
GRAPHICS CARD
（显卡盒）
That's quite a gap.
落差有够大…